guys. I think it was a successful start
to our draft. Very excited to get Wena
here in Baltimore. He's a guy that we've
studied at length. We had a chance to
spend some time with him at the combine
and also um here in Baltimore at length.
Great, great kid, excellent player.
Obviously have a lot of ties to the Penn
State football program. Had the chance
to watch him play a couple years at both
left and right uh guard. Physical uh
tough, very athletic for his size,
excellent in pass protection, a great
fit for our offense and what we're
trying to accomplish. Um and we're just
very very happy to have him here. So, um
questions.
>> Eric, when it came to 14, because there
were a couple surprises up there for you
guys. Uh, did you consider it an easy
decision once you looked at the board?
What were you going with?
>> Uh, you know, I wouldn't say it was easy
decision. Uh, you know, there were
certainly some really good players still
available, guys that we really liked
quite a bit. Um, but in the end, I think
as we looked at it and just talked to
our scouts and our coaches especially,
we felt that Wenger was the best pick
for us.
>> Eric, did you have interest in that
pick? Was were you weighing any trade uh
possibilities when you were at the
clock? Um we we did get a call that just
kind of ended up just falling apart. Um
we did consider potentially a trade
back, but it had would have to have made
sense for us based on the players still
available and the amount of players that
we really wanted at that spot. So for us
to go back basically we would have had
to ensure that we would have gotten one
of a handful of players. Um it didn't
really materialize at the end and the
other team decided they wanted to make
the pick and clarified things for us. It
was easy for us to turn the card in at
that time.
>> Jesse, your first term as the head coach
in that in that war room. What was your
experience like tonight?
>> It was great. Um, I mean, these guys do
a phenomenal job and we, you know, I
think between the coaches, the front
office, we all put a lot of work into
evaluating players and kind of figuring
out what we're looking for. Um, you
know, the guy that we got, I think, as a
first pick is is the epitome of what we
want the team to be like. you know, line
of scrimmage, dominant team. Uh, so
really physical, really great player,
really great person. Really enjoyed
getting to know him a little bit on the
visit and, uh, he's everything that we
want our guys to be.
>> Jesse, do you anticipate him being at
left guard?
>> I think we'll figure that all out. I
mean, he's a great player. He's played
he's actually played guard, both guards.
He actually started one game at center a
couple years ago. So, I think he's got a
lot a lot of versatility and we'll
figure out the best uh best way to get
our best players on the field.
>> Eric, when you look at how much you have
invested in Lamar, how much you have
invested in Henry, um do you feel like
sort of um definitely I mean sort of
investing even that investment so to
speak in making sure that your backfield
is protected.
>> I think that's right. you know, we want
to be a we want to be a strong imposing
team and uh you know, we we probably
haven't invested as many resources in
the offensive line recently. Um I don't
you I think other than probably uh Tyler
Linderbomb, this is the first first
round pick we've used in an offensive
lineman probably since Ronnie Stanley.
Before that, I believe probably Ben
Grubs, maybe 2007, and we doubled up
that year with Yonder and Grubs. So, I I
think this guy just really checked off
every single box for us as a player. Uh
mentality, personality, ability, skill
level, athletic ability, physicality,
all those different things. Um at a at a
very high level and uh you know, we love
when we can get the best player at his
position in the draft, which we've done
a lot, and kind of take pride in that.
Um so, we think he's a great fit for us
and certainly going to help the players
around him on the offensive line. uh
they'll help him as well, but I think
he's going to make us better and really
make the middle of our offense very
strong.
>> Jesse, I know you guys have spent
extensive time with with him and other
prospects, but I guess the first time we
got to meet him, he described himself
big described himself as a mer and he
specifically said, "I'm not going to let
anyone touch my quarterback." I guess
just with this being your first night as
head coach, what's your reaction to
that? Does it give you a charge on?
>> Yeah, that gives me a real charge. um
you know that's when you when you meet
him and you get to know him that's his
mentality but he also has like this
humility about him which kind of uh just
sparks like how hard he works and he
doesn't he doesn't assume that he's
going to be a great player. He puts in
the work and the time um and just really
man just couldn't be more excited to add
his mentality the way that he plays his
play style really matches what we're
trying to do. Jesse, what did Dwayne
Leford? What was his reaction and what
was his evaluation? What he had to say
about the video?
>> I think coach Leadford was pretty
excited. Uh there may be a video that
comes out at some point where you'll see
his reaction. Uh but he was very
excited. Obviously, he uh is a guy that
we put a lot of time in the eval
process. Um probably, you know, very
very very very high up there on coach
Sledford's list of favorite players in
the draft and uh worked out for us.
Eric, you you love the misdirection
before the draft and not being
predictable. Were you concerned in the
days ahead of this draft that so many
people were connecting you to uh Wenger
that it might he might get away from you
and teams would trade up in front of you
to get him?
>> You know, you're always a little
concerned. You're not you're not really
sure, especially where there's some
teams picking in front of us that know
us pretty well. Um
kind of similar last year with Starks, I
think. Um, but in the end, you know, we
just kind of stick to the board and and
let the board fall to us, which is
something I learned from Azie many years
ago. And uh, you know, sometimes it
works out, sometimes it doesn't. And if
it hadn't worked out, we had other
players that we would have picked,
excellent players. So, I thought I I
said we were in a good spot um, leading
up to the draft and it sort of played
out that way for us for what we wanted
to accomplish with our team, with our
roster. There were several players that
really would have fit us this year and
helped make us a better football team.
Fortunately, we got one of our favorite
guys.
>> Go ahead. Sorry. Go ahead.
>> Were you surprised Bane was still there
that he fell,
>> you know, he's a great player, too. Um,
and you know, and I think, uh, you know,
a player that, you know, again, another
guy, he's, you know, a great selection
by the Bucks, I think would have made a
great Raven. You know, those are the
tough decisions that we have to make.
Um, but in the end, I really feel like
we got a guy that really fits us
personalitywise and abilitywise and just
everything that we want our guys to be.
I think, you know, Venga kind of
epitomizes that and we're excited to see
what he can do.
>> Eric, um, you've touched on this a
little bit. Steve mentioned obviously
back in January. Um, you know, best
player available, but but did you feel
like offensive line was really the most
important need for you guys and to
address that really early on? I
>> I mean, I think is definitely one of the
one of the positions that we we
prioritized. there were some others and
there are some others and we'll continue
to hopefully have a chance to address
those players. I need some more picks,
you know, cuz there's some good players
that are going to be available, but uh
we do hope to, you know, definitely
attack some other position groups as
well. Um I think that just, you know,
when you think you're good with the
roster, things happen, right? And so we
want to be strong at every position with
as much depth as possible. And uh that's
why we're excited, I think, about the
next couple days and the amount of picks
that we have and the opportunities that
present themselves. Eric, I mentioned I
think in the first round tonight, nine
offensive line were taken. How good has
what, you know, in just going leading up
to this draft, how good did you think
this offensive line class was?
>> I mean, I think very deep. Very deep.
And and the fact is, you know, there's
still some really good players. I mean,
normally if you saw nine players going
any given round, you would think that it
was going to thin out really quickly.
And I think still now looking at that
those positions, there's still some
excellent football players available.
And I I think it speaks to the cyclical
nature of the draft. Every year there's
different positions that are strong and
other positions maybe not quite as
strong. Last year happened to be, you
know, defensive line was really strong.
Um this year I think offensive line
certainly one of the better positions in
the draft and I think the other teams to
recognize that as well.
>> Eric, you mentioned that you feel that
uh Venga is best at his position in this
draft.
>> Um you know relative to other guards, I
mean did you feel something about his
ceiling and his, you know, technical
ability or physical gifts
>> made it important to get the best guy at
guard relative to other guards in the
draft. I know that might be complicated
because you might draft more guards
here.
>> Yeah. So, for me, a big thing is just
watching the tape and evaluating and
seeing everything, how the guy does all
those testing and things and talking to
people. But a big part of the process
for me is really meeting with the
players.
And that's really a way for me to, you
know, separate these guys. I mean, you
know, I've been blessed to be here 30
years and I can't imagine how many
players I've met, but you start to build
up a bank of memories and different
interviews and different players and
things. And meeting him uh was
impressive and uh left an impression
with me. He reminds me, and I told him
this and he laughed. He said because
somebody else has told him this, he
reminds me a little bit of one of my
favorite Ravens of all time, Hodata. uh
and just the way that he was with me in
the office and we were talking and
laughing and his maturity um and the way
that he even though he's a younger
person, even the way that he carried
himself with a quiet confidence stood
out. So, you know, uh in the end, as
you're trying to split all these guys
up, because these guys are all really
good players, they're the best in the
world and what they do in college
football. In the end, these these
interviews and these visits, they end up
really kind of beingcoming the nuance of
how you kind of split hairs with these
guys. I mean, you you've talked about
some of the challenges of taking a guard
in the first round because of the fifth
year valuation aspect of it. Um,
>> so to take a guard that high, I mean, do
you do you essentially have to believe
that that could be a Pro Bowl player,
that it could be one of the best guys in
the league at that position?
>> I mean, that would be the hope, you
know, that would be the goal. I think
that we have seen the the guard market
start to mirror more of the tackle
market. Uh, we saw this year the center
market trying to catch up. I think you
know teams people are realizing that
these offensive linemen are special
athletes who who do very unique things.
Um they're hard to find and so that
market has grown and changed and and
will adjust with it. But again um I
firmly believe that this guy is going to
be a really really good player with us
for the next five years and hopefully
longer than that. Um there are obvious
obviously challenges um with the way
that that offensive line kind of frarier
option is all kind of encompassed with
tackles, guards, and centers. But I'm
not going to worry about that today.
That's something for me to worry about
three years from now.
>> Eric, beyond just, you know, fortifying
and pass protection and how important
was it to get someone who could be a
people mover in the run game because,
you know, we know just how much of those
running lanes for Derek only amplified
his talents.
I mean, I think that's been, you know, a
hallmark of the Ravens over the last
seven years is the ability to run the
football and and be a physical downhill
team that can just take over games and
crunch time in the fourth quarter and
put teams away. And so, uh, I think I
think Vanar really fits that mentality
in the way that he plays. And I think,
um, I think it's a really good fit for
us in terms of what we like to be up
front. And, uh, I think our fan base is
going to love them, too.
>> Eric, I know you like look for every
piece of little information. There there
was a viral video of him like leaping
over and I saw
>> that. Does that leave an impress? Does
that even
>> Yeah. I mean, you know, those things we
we look at all that stuff, you know. I
think, you know, there was another
player that uh I I watched his high
school wrestling videos. Um all that
stuff matters in some little small way,
you know, and so yeah, I saw that he
helps the guy push the thing. Yeah.
Yeah, that was really cool. Um I think
it speaks to his humility and uh just
who he is as a person, how his parents
raised him, for sure. Um but yeah, I
mean all that stuff we look at all that
social media, you know, I always tell my
kids be careful because people like me
are scouring the internet looking at
your social media, you know. Um so yeah,
I think that stuff's really important.
>> Jesse, what um just from a technical
football standpoint, what stood out to
you most about it?
>> You know, I think like especially with a
guard, he's not he's not scheme
dependent. So this guy could run any
type of run scheme, any type of pass
blocking scheme. It's not like, well,
he, you know, he fits in a scheme where
they turn and run or he fits in a scheme
where they double team people. He can do
all that. And he also lined up as a
offthe- ball tight end with motion and
knock people out, you know, slice
blocking and things like that. So, I
just think the the versatility to really
do everything at a really high level,
his athleticism, and then I think when
you watch the tape, his play style and
his play demeanor, you can sort of feel
like he's really trying to, you know,
block these guys like really really with
a with the right mindset. And so, I
think all that really jumps off when you
watch this tape.
Eric, just touching on another piece of
news. Uh Zay Flowers, a two-time pro
bowler for you. Was it important for you
guys to um pick up his fifth year option
and ideally would you like to see an
extension uh done at some point in in
the future?
>> Yeah, for sure. I mean, I actually was
shocked you guys didn't ask me about
that at the uh draft press conference.
The first time in how many years,
Jameson? It's been a while, you know. Um
but what I I would of course I would
have told you guys. Uh no, we're fired
up. Um I love Zay. He's he's he's earned
this. Uh he's a tremendous player with a
great work ethic and a great
personality. Infectious, very talented.
He's a leader and uh the goal would be
to get along to him, deal with him if we
can, and I I fully expect we will.
>> He's got a great agent and he's a he's a
great person. I know he wants to be
here.
>> My apologies. Um Eric, there were
reports a few days ago that Naomi Matabk
underwent surgery last week. Um focus on
the draft, but just anything you can
share about that and the idea that you
guys might be hopeful he'll be able to
play.
Yeah, you know, um there's not much I
can say. Uh I will say Nambi's here, you
know, he is here in the build. Not
tonight, but he's here now um in the
program, offseason program. Um but you
know, uh that's internal business. It's
his business. If he wants to say
anything about anything, he's more than
welcome to. But as a club, I think our
policy is to protect the players and not
have any kind of statements regarding
their health or anything personal like
that. Um, but he is here and he's going
to be here as far as I know. Um, and
we're excited about that.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.